Guide to the Hilbert Fefferman papers, 1946-2002.
Fefferman, Hilbert papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Hilbert Fefferman papers, 1946-2002.
8421
Fefferman, Hilbert.
1 cubic feet.
Correspondence, photographs, publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence, 1946-2002 on housing and financing issues and journal articles. Also, signed photographs of George Romney and Robert Weaver and a HUD Distinguished Service Award certificate.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Hilbert Fefferman served as chief legislative attorney for the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development from 1941 until 1972. He was also a visiting professor of city planning at MIT and special counsel for Fannie Mae in Washington. He was responsible for drafting major federal and state legislation relating to housing and urban development, including the creation of Fannie Mae and modern mortgage secondary market financing, civil rights developments, and the reconstruction of cities through urban renewal.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, 1946-2002 on housing and financing issues and journal articles. Also, signed photographs of George Romney and Robert Weaver and a HUD Distinguished Service Award certificate.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Fefferman, Hilbert.; Federal National Mortgage Association.; United States. Department of Housing and Urban Development -- Officials and employees.
Subjects:
City planning.; Housing.; Mortgage loans.; Secondary mortgage market.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Vitae and bibliographics, 1970-1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1946-1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1961-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1970-1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1980-2002 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Oversight hearings, "Urban Growth and New Community Development Act of 1970", 1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Coan, Couture, Lyons and Moorhead biographics, 1981-1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Fannie Mac, 1978-1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Harvard - critical legal studies, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Moe Fleissig, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- McFarland book, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- "Where We Live", 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Lloyd Rodwin, 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Wilmer, Cutler and Pickering, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Journal articles, 1947-1997 (Box 1)
- Signed photographs of George Romney and Robert Weaver (Box 2)
- Group photograph (Box 2)
- HUD Distinguished Service Award certificate (Box 2)
- FNMA, presentation to real estate analyst group with Q & A, David O. Maxwell [tape cassette], 1983; TR-10526 (Box 2)
- Small flyer for 1999 annual housing conference, encased in acrylic, 1999 (Box 2)
- Group photo of Dutch housing officials and Hilbert Fefferman, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Photo of Hilbert and Helen Fefferman, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- HUD Proposal, legislative draft, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Charles M. Haar items, 1992, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- The American Institute of Architects, National Housing Policy, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- "My Temporary Job in Washington," Ashley Foard, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 6)